A Guide to the Bureau of Social Hygiene records FA060
Rockefeller Archive Center
Bureau of Social Hygiene records
1911-1940
Rockefeller Archive Center
Bureau of Social Hygiene. (New York, N.Y.)
Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar)
Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano)
Dunham, Lawrence Boardman
Flexner, Abraham
Fosdick, Raymond B. (Raymond Blaine)
Murphy, Starr
Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison)
Rockefeller, John D.
FA060
31.2 Cubic Feet 78 document cases
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged in six series, as follows:
Series 1 - Administration
Series 2 - Finances
Series 3 - Projects
Series 4 - Leonard V. Harrison Files
Series 5 - New York Police Psychopathic Laboratory
Series 1017 - Photographs
Biographical/Historical note
The Bureau of Social Hygiene resulted from the appointment of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., to a Special Grand Jury to investigate white slavery in New York City in 1910. In conferences taken in the course of this investigation, Mr. Rockefeller, Jr., became convinced that for a lasting improvement of conditions a permanent organization was needed. On March 22, 1911, The Committee of Three, including Mr. Rockefeller, Jr., Paul Warburg, and Starr Murphy, met. The name "Bureau of Social Hygiene" was first used in October of that year, but not consistently until 1913.
In 1913 the Bureau was incorporated and its purpose was stated as "...the study, amelioration, and prevention of those social conditions, crimes, and diseases which adversely affect the well being of society, with special reference to prostitution and the evils associated therewith." The Bureau would engage in research and education, publish reports, and employ and/or cooperate with other public or private agencies to obtain these goals. The emphasis in the years from 1911 until the reorganization of 1928 was mainly on prostitution, the control of vice, and, through that, the relationships to police organization. Narcotics was also an early interest. Throughout these early years, Katherine Bement Davis, Commissioner of Charities and Correction of New York and later Superintendent of Bedford Hills Reformatory, guided the Bureau as General Secretary.
Miss Davis resigned in 1928 and Lawrence B. Dunham was appointed Director. Under Mr. Dunham's administration, from 1928-1934, the Bureau developed a broadened interest in criminology. In 1929 the certificate of incorporation was amended and the emphasis on prostitution was dropped. Criminology embraced crime reporting, police training and education, penology, criminal law, and juvenile delinquency. While studies and projects were still conducted in narcotics and social hygiene, the main thrust of the organization was crime and criminology.
The Bureau functioned through grants. It was not a foundation and had no set endowment. In the very early years of its existence, financial backing came from several sources including Paul Warburg, the New York Foundation, and John D. Rockefeller, Jr., although throughout the history of the Bureau, Mr. Rockefeller, Jr., was always the main contributor. Grants were occasionally channeled through the Bureau from the Spelman Fund of New York and the Rockefeller Foundation.
Grants were made by the Bureau for a variety of types of work. Research studies were conducted, such as the Institute of Criminology and the Crew Study; books were published, such as "European Police Systems" and "Policewoman's Handbook"; fellowships were given, as were the fellowships in prison study; and experiments were conducted at the Massachusetts State Prison Colony and the Laboratory of Social Hygiene at Bedford Hills. Grants were most often long range covering periods of from three to five years. Although the Bureau did not interfere in the conduct of a project once money had been granted, it was careful in its selection of projects and kept in close touch during the life of the project.
The Bureau ceased making new appropriations in 1934 and by mid-1937 all the previous commitments had been brought to a close. Annual meetings were held until 1940 when the Bureau was dissolved on November 13th.
Scope and Contents note
Important subjects in this collection include: prostitution and white slavery, penal institutions and systems, juvenile delinquency, criminal law, police systems, police training, public administration, narcotics laws and control nationally and internationally, maternal health, sex education, birth control, uniform crime statistics, the relation of mental illness to crime, scientific criminal investigations, probation and parole.
Among the correspondents are: Raymond B. Fosdick, Starr Murphy, Arthur Woods, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Henry Aslinger, William Draper Lewis, John D. Rockefeller, 3rd, Abraham Flexner, Walter L. Treadway, Felix Frankfurter, J. Edgar Hoover, George Wickersham, Katharine B. Davis, Leonard V. Harrison, Franklin D. Roosevelt, James Bronson Reynolds, Lawrence B. Dunham, and Alfred E. Smith.
It was not the Bureau's practice to keep the research files from any given project. Thus the records for the Sanger Birth Control Clinic are at Harvard, the Laboratory of Social Hygiene records are at Bedford Hills, and so on.
The Bureau of Social Hygiene Collection covers the period from 1911 to 1940.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for scholarly research without restriction.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IV 2B 03
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The papers of the Bureau of Social Hygiene were deposited with the Rockefeller Foundation Archives in January 1938 by Arthur Woods.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Maternal health services; Narcotic laws; Public health administration; Police training; Juvenile delinquency; Criminal law; Crime; Correctional institutions; Mental health; Family planning; Hygiene; Human rights; Law; Mentally ill offenders; Birth control; Sexual health; Prostitution; Human trafficking; United States; Bureau of Social Hygiene. (New York, N.Y.); Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar); Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano); Dunham, Lawrence Boardman; Flexner, Abraham; Fosdick, Raymond B. (Raymond Blaine); Murphy, Starr; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller, John D.; Bureau of Social Hygiene. (New York, N.Y.); Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar); Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano); Dunham, Lawrence Boardman; Flexner, Abraham; Fosdick, Raymond B. (Raymond Blaine); Murphy, Starr; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller, John D.
- Administration, 1
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of annual reports, dockets, the Bureau history, minutes, and folders for the members and staff of the Bureau. While there is reference to the various projects, the emphasis of this series is on administration policy.
  - Annual Report, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    This folder contains information on the Crew Study.
  - Annual Report, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report Correspondence, 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Armour, Alexander, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Colby, Everett, 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Davis, Katherine, 1925-1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Debevoise, Thomas, 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dockets, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dockets, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dockets, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dockets, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dunham, Lawrence, 1927-1936 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Farnham, John, 1929-1936 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Fosdick, Raymond, 1914-1933 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Harrison, Leonard, 1932-1936 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - History - Organization and Bylaws (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - History - Reorganization, 1915-1916 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - History - Reorganization, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - History - Working Plans (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - History - Termination, 1932-1935 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Meetings, 1930-1935 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Minutes, 1911-1916 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Minutes, 1911-1916 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Minutes, 1911-1916 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Minutes, 1911-1916 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Minutes, 1911-1916 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Minutes, 1911-1916 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Minutes, 1917-1940 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Packard, A. W., 1930-1934 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Plazinski, Thaddeus, 1930-1935 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Publications (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1912-1933 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd., 1931-1934 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1930-1933 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Sellin, Thorsten, 1930-1933 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Social Sciences, 1921-1930 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Spelman Fund Appropriations, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Sutherland, E. H., 1929-1935 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Sutherland, E. H., 1929-1935 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Topping, Ruth, 1930-1932 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Winsor, Max, 1931-1934 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Woods, Arthur, 1926-1934 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Woods, Arthur, 1926-1934 (Box 4, Folder 64)
- Finances, 2
  This series is arranged alphabetically and chronologically.
  This series included budgets, accounts, treasurer's reports, royalty information on the publications, and pledges and commitments.
  Related Archival Materials note
  The following Bureau financial records are located in JDR financial material: Ledger, Oct. 1, 1925 Cash Journal and Trial Balance, 1920-1924 Ledger, 1926-January 18, 1928
  See also China Medical Board, Inc. Collection, Series 2, Box 5 for Trial Balance, 1928-1930.
  - Accountant's Reports, 1928-1934 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Budgets, 1928-1932 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Billerica Trust Company, 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence, 1928-1933 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Financial Reports, 1911-1934 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Income Tax, 1928-1933 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Mt. Kisco National Bank and Trust, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Norfolk Prison Report, 1934-1940 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - "The Opium Problem", 1937 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Pledges and Commitments
    - Pledges and Commitments, 1928-1935 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Pledges and Commitments, 1928-1935 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Pledges and Commitments, 1928-1935 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Pledges and Commitments, 1928-1935 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Pledges and Commitments, 1928-1935 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Pledges and Commitments, 1928-1935 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Pledges and Commitments, 1928-1935 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Pledges and Commitments - John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1911-1940 (Box 1, Folder 80A)
  - Project Reports (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Project Financial Reports, 1929-1935 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Publication Agreements (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Publications (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Publications - Correspondence, 1913-1945 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Resolutions, 1926-1934 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Resolutions, 1926-1934 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Disposition of Royalties (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Salary Schedules, 1928-1932 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Tax, Capital Stock, 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Tax, Gift Donees, 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1928-1940 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Unemployment Insurance, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Accounts, 1919-1921 (Box 2, Folder 93A)
  - Accounts, 1922-June 1923 (Box 2, Folder 93B)
  - Accounts, July 1923-June 1924 (Box 2, Folder 93C)
  - Accounts, July 1924-May 1926 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Accounts, June 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 93E)
  - Cash Book, 1928-1940 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Journal, 1928-1940 (Box 3, Folder 93G)
  - Ledger, 1928-1939 (Box 3, Folder 93H)
  - Trial Balance, 1930-1939 (Box 3, Folder 93I)
- Projects, 3
  This series is arranged in five subseries, as follows:
  Subseries 1 - Narcotics (6 boxes)
  Subseries 2 - Social Hygiene (4 boxes)
  Subseries 3 - Juvenile Delinquency (4 boxes)
  Subseries 4 - Criminology (23 boxes)
  Subseries 5 - Miscellaneous (3 boxes)
  This series contains project information, as well as general subject information. These files date mainly from the 1928 reorganization through 1935.
  Existence and Location of Copies
  Scholarly access to original archival material is permitted. User copies of microfilm are also available. The Projects series is reproduced in the microfilm publication of the Bureau of Social Hygiene project and research files, 1913-1940, reels 1-20 (Scholarly Resources Inc., 1980).
  - Projects - Narcotics, 3_1
    This subseries contains information on publications such as "Dangerous Drugs", the League of Nations Committee, narcotics investigations, and legislation in the area of narcotics control.
    - American White Cross Association on Drug Addiction, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Caldwell, Kenneth, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Case Histories, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Committee on Traffic in Opium, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Dai, Bingham, 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - "Dangerous Drugs" by Arthur Woods, 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - "Dangerous Drugs" by Arthur Woods, 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - "Dangerous Drugs" by Arthur Woods, 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - "Dangerous Drugs" by Arthur Woods, 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Farnham, John, 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - Farnham, John, 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Farnham, John, 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Farnham, John, 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Farnham, John, 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Farnham, John, 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Farnham, John - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Gavit, John, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - League of Nations, 1920-1934 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - League of Nations, 1920-1934 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - League of Nations, 1920-1934 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - League of Nations, 1920-1934 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - League of Nations, 1920-1934 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - League of Nations, 1920-1934 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - League of Nations, 1920-1934 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - League of Nations, 1920-1934 (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - League of Nations, 1920-1934 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - League of Nations - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Maritime Insurance, 1927-1929 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Massachusetts Narcotics Survey, 1930-1931 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Narcotics, 1924-1931 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Narcotics, 1924-1931 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Narcotics, 1924-1931 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Narcotics, 1924-1931 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Narcotics, 1924-1931 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Narcotics, 1924-1931 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Narcotics, 1932-1935 (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - Narcotics, 1932-1935 (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Narcotics, 1932-1935 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Narcotics, 1932-1935 (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Narcotics - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Narcotics - Investigations, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Narcotics - Manufacturers, 1928-1933 (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Narcotics - Seizure Cases, 1926-1930 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - National Research Council Committee on Drug Addiction, 1922-1928 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - National Research Council Committee on Drug Addiction, 1922-1928 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - National Research Council Committee on Drug Addiction, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 142)
    - National Research Council Committee on Drug Addiction, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 143)
    - National Research Council Committee on Drug Addiction, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 144)
    - National Research Council Committee on Drug Addiction, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 145)
    - National Research Council Committee on Drug Addiction, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 146)
    - National Research Council Committee on Drug Addiction - Clippings and Pamphlets, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 147)
    - National Research Council Committee on Drug Addiction - Reports, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 148)
    - Nutt, L. C., 1926-1929 (Box 5, Folder 149)
    - Opium, 1926-1931 (Box 5, Folder 150)
    - Opium Advisory Committee, 1926-1933 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - "The Opium Problem" by Terry and Pellens, 1928-1934 (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - Opium Production in Persia, 1925-1928 (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Porter Bills, 1929-1930 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Porter Bills - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - "Report on the Legal Use of Narcotics in Detroit, Michigan and Its Environs", 1930-1931 (Box 6, Folder 156)
    - "Report on the Legal Use of Narcotics in Detroit, Michigan and Its Environs", 1930-1931 (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - "Report on the Legal Use of Narcotics in Detroit, Michigan and Its Environs" - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Underhill, Frank, 1927-1928 (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - Uniform State Narcotics Laws, 1929-1932 (Box 6, Folder 160)
    - Uniform State Narcotics Laws - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 161)
  - Projects - Social Hygiene, 3_2
    This subseries includes material on white slavery and prostitution, birth control, sex education, eugenics, venereal disease, and population.
    - American Birth Control League, 1929-1936 (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - American Birth Control League, 1929-1936 (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - American Social Hygiene Association Vice Investigations, 1930-1934 (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - American Social Hygiene Association Vice Investigations - Reports (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - Birth Control, 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau, 1931-1935 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - Boston Dispensary, 1929-1930 (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - British Social Hygiene Council, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Canadian Social Hygiene Council, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - "Commercialized Prostitution in New York" by George Kneeland (Box 7, Folder 171)
    - Committee on Maternal Health, 1923-1934 (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - Committee on Maternal Health, 1923-1934 (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - Committee on Maternal Health, 1923-1934 (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - Committee on Maternal Health - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - Cooperative Donor Bureau for Blood Transfusion, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 176)
    - "Eugenical Sterilization in the U. S." by Laughlin, 1920-1921 (Box 8, Folder 177)
    - Eugenics, 1924-1934 (Box 8, Folder 178)
    - "Factors in the Sex Life of 2200 Women" by Katherine Davis, 1930-1933 (Box 8, Folder 179)
    - Federation Abolitionniste Internationale, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 180)
    - International Federation of Eugenical Organization, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 181)
    - Johns Hopkins University Department of Syphilis, 1914-1915 (Box 8, Folder 182)
    - Kopp, Marie, 1932-1934 (Box 8, Folder 183)
    - Lexington Investigation, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 184)
    - National Research Council Committee on Sex Research, 1927-1932 (Box 8, Folder 185)
    - National Research Council Committee on Sex Research, 1927-1932 (Box 8, Folder 186)
    - National Research Council Committee on Sex Research, 1927-1932 (Box 8, Folder 187)
    - National Research Council Committee on Sex Research - Reports (Box 8, Folder 188)
    - National Research Council Committee on Sex Research - Reports (Box 8, Folder 189)
    - Population, 1931-1933 (Box 9, Folder 190)
    - Population Conference, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 191)
    - "Prostitution in America" by Abraham Flexner, 1914-1918 (Box 9, Folder 192)
    - "Prostitution in America" by Abraham Flexner, 1914-1918 (Box 9, Folder 193)
    - "Prostitution in America" by Abraham Flexner, 1914-1918 (Box 9, Folder 194)
    - "Prostitution in Europe" by Abraham Flexner, 1910-1912 (Box 9, Folder 195)
    - "Prostitution in Europe" by Abraham Flexner - Translations (Box 9, Folder 196)
    - Prostitution - Regulation, 1912-1917 (Box 9, Folder 197)
    - Prostitution - Regulation, 1912-1917 (Box 9, Folder 198)
    - Regional Conference in Social Hygiene, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 199)
    - "A Research in Marriage" by G. V. Hamilton, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 200)
    - Sex Education, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 201)
    - Social Hygiene, 1928-1934 (Box 10, Folder 202)
    - Survey of Traffic in Women and Children, 1928-1933 (Box 10, Folder 203)
    - Third International Congress of Eugenics, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 204)
    - University of Minnesota, 1929-1931 (Box 10, Folder 205)
    - University of Minnesota, 1929-1931 (Box 10, Folder 206)
    - University of Minnesota, 1929-1931 (Box 10, Folder 207)
    - University of Minnesota - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 208)
    - Venereal Disease, 1931-1933 (Box 10, Folder 209)
    - Venereal Disease, 1931-1933 (Box 10, Folder 210)
    - Venereal Disease - Pamphlets (Box 10, Folder 211)
    - White House Conference in Child Health and Protection, 1930-1931 (Box 10, Folder 212)
    - World Population Conference (Box 10, Folder 213)
  - Projects - Juvenile Delinquency, 3_3
    This subseries contains information on detention homes, boys clubs, adolescent courts, and the New York University Boys Club Study.
    - Adolescent Court, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 214)
      Correspondence about the establishment of a court in New York.
    - Boys' Clubs, 1927-1931 (Box 11, Folder 215)
      New York City.
    - Brooklyn Continuation School, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 216)
    - Committee on Boys in Prison, 1930-1931 (Box 11, Folder 217)
    - Delinquency, 1930-1936 (Box 11, Folder 218)
    - Delinquency Study, 1929-1930 (Box 11, Folder 219)
      New York.
    - East Harlem Health Center, 1925-1926 (Box 11, Folder 220)
    - Gang Study, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 221)
    - Girls Schools, 1931-1933 (Box 11, Folder 222)
    - House of Refuge, 1927-1928 (Box 11, Folder 223)
      Randall's Island, New York City.
    - Hudson Avenue Club for Colored Boys, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 224)
    - Institute for Juvenile Research, 1930-1932 (Box 11, Folder 225)
    - International Boys Work Council, 1927-1928 (Box 11, Folder 226)
    - New York University Boys Club Study, 1927-1932 (Box 11, Folder 227)
    - New York University Boys Club Study, 1927-1932 (Box 11, Folder 228)
    - New York University Boys Club Study, 1927-1932 (Box 11, Folder 229)
    - New York University Boys Club Study, 1927-1932 (Box 11, Folder 230)
    - New York University Boys Club Study, 1927-1932 (Box 11, Folder 231)
    - New York University Boys Club Study, 1933-1936 (Box 12, Folder 232)
    - New York University Boys Club Study - Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 233)
    - "Jefferson Park Boys Club" by Frederick Thrasher - Volume 1 (Box 12, Folder 233A)
    - "Jefferson Park Boys Club" by Frederick Thrasher - Volume 2 (Box 12, Folder 233B)
    - "Jefferson Park Boys Club" by Frederick Thrasher - Volume 3 (Box 12, Folder 233C)
    - "Jefferson Park Boys Club" by Frederick Thrasher - Volume 4 (Box 13, Folder 233)
    - "Jefferson Park Boys Club" by Frederick Thrasher - Volume 5 (Box 13, Folder 233E)
    - "Jefferson Park Boys Club" by Frederick Thrasher - Volume 6 (Box 13, Folder 233)
    - Judge Baker Foundation, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 234)